### Contact

+14158124715 (Mobile) stas@vitko.me

www.linkedin.com/in/vitkostanislav (LinkedIn) stas.vitko.me (Personal)

## Top Skills

Cloud Computing
Machine Learning
Kubernetes

### Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure

Architecting with Google Cloud Platform Specialization

Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services

Architecting with Google Compute Engine Specialization

# Stanislav Vitko

DevOps team lead at Grid Dynamics.

San Francisco, California

# Summary

I am leading an international team of brilliant Software Engineers building infrastructure automation solutions for highly-scalable, distributed e-commerce systems.

Have experience in the design and implementation of deployment orchestration systems for massive, distributed monoliths.

I'm helping to bring DevOps culture and practices to engineering teams and automate all the things.

Cloud platforms: GCP, AWS and Digital Ocean for side projects. Programming: Python, Go. Used Java, Fortran, Ruby, and Scala for personal projects.

# Experience

Grid Dynamics 8 years 6 months

San Francisco Bay Area

Team Lead/Development Manager February 2016 - Present (4 years 1 month)

Grid Dynamics is the engineering IT services company known for transformative, mission-critical cloud solutions for retail, finance, and technology sectors.

- Lead distributed Software Engineering team of 30 engineers working on internal tooling and development process automation.
- Grew the team in multiple locations in the US and Europe.
- Designed and build a self-service cloud-based deployment orchestration platform, which increased release frequency from monthly to weekly releases.
- Designed and executed an experiment on migration production workloads to Kubernetes. Achieved a 60% reduction in resource footprint for user-facing applications providing the same level of service.

Software Development Manager

### September 2011 - February 2016 (4 years 6 months)

Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

- Lead DevOps team in Saint-Petersburg (Russia). Hired the team in the new engineering center, Kharkiv (Ukraine). Extended San Francisco team.
- Build Jenkins-centric CI/CD processes, automated testing, and developed chef-based deployment automation for ~100 Java and NodeJS based applications. Speed up delivery and reduce downtimes in production.
- Migrate development workloads to Google Cloud Platform, significantly reduce the costs of development infrastructure.
- Initialized process of consolidation of deployment tools across the organization to reduce duplication and unify deployments.

#### **Fides**

IT consultant

June 2011 - September 2011 (4 months)

IT consulting. Audit existing infrastructure, services, and processes. Prepared a reorganization plan.

### Visual Trading Systems

System Administrator

April 2008 - June 2011 (3 years 3 months)

Visual Trading Systems specializes in the IT needs of the Forex trading.

- Monitoring and support of high loaded production servers for Forex trading.
- Migrate storage systems from on-prem to AWS S3 and EC2.

### Altitudo

System Administrator

June 2006 - March 2008 (1 year 10 months)

- Designed build and support shared WEB hosting platform for the clients.
- Helped to organize Worldwide developers conference Sun Tech Days in Saint Petersburg, Russia.

## Education

Saint Petersburg State University

postgraduate student, Physics, Math, Computer Science · (2010 - 2012)

Saint Petersburg State University

Master's Degree, Physics, Math, Computer Science (2004 - 2010)